accessdata.com 2017-11-07

# Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement applies to the accessdata.com website (“website”). AccessData (“AccessData”), “we”, “our” or “us”) respects your preferences concerning the treatment of personal information that we may collect from your association with us.

**Your Acceptance of this Privacy Statement**  
By using this website, purchasing from us, or participating in an AccessData service or program, you signify your acceptance of the terms and conditions of this Privacy Statement.

**Changes to Privacy Statement**  
We may update this Privacy Statement from time to time. When we post changes to this Privacy Statement, we will revise the “last updated” date at the top of this Privacy Statement. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Statement.

**Information Collected**  
During the sales process, or through trade shows, marketing events, and other activities, you consent to the collection and storage of your information. For example, we request information from you when you:

  * Register on accessdata.com
  * Request a demo disk
  * Request a quotation or information
  * Register for a webinar, seminar, or other informational event
  * Place an order
  * Participate in a sweepstakes or other promotional offer
  * Subscribe to a newsletter or a mailing list
  * Request assistance from us

We may ask you for your name, postal address, country, e-mail address, password, telephone number, type of business, license key, customer account number and credit card information, as well as other similar personal information.

You may voluntarily provide us with personal and other information and comments and content in connection with using this website.

We may automatically collect other information about you, including Web browser type, Internet Protocol address, domain name of Internet service provider, geographic location, website pages visited and times of visit and aggregated information that cannot be used to specifically identify you when you use or visit this website.

**How We Use Your Information**  
The information you provide will be used to support and enhance your relationship with us. Among other things, your information may be used to alert you to product upgrades or special offers, and to market or sell our products or services to you, including via email. Your information may be combined with information collected about you by us or third parties, with information that is collected about you from public records, or with information that we may acquire from third parties.

**Data Sharing and Transfer**  
Information may be disclosed to third parties in accordance with this Privacy Statement. We may disclose your information with third parties with whom we have partnered to provide specific services to us or services on our behalf.

In addition, we may be required to disclose your information to third parties to comply with law or in response to subpoenas, warrants, or court orders or in connection with law enforcement, fraud prevention, regulation, and other legal action or if we reasonably believe it is necessary to do so to protect us, our customers, or the public.

If we become involved in a merger, consolidation, acquisition, sale of assets, joint venture, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, liquidation, dissolution, or other transaction or if the ownership of all or substantially all of our business otherwise changes, we may share or transfer your information to a third party or parties in connection therewith.

We may disclose your information to any subsidiary or affiliate of ours.

Please also see Cookies, Web Beacons, Do Not Track and Online Tracking below regarding disclosing information to third parties.

**Changing Your Account Information**  
If you wish to see information you have provided us with, request changes to or deletion thereof or provide us with additional information, please email us at [legal@accessdata.com](mailto:legal@accessdata.com).

**Data Security and Responsibility**  
We take seriously the trust you place in us. We utilize reasonable physical, technical, and administrative procedures to safeguard the information we collect.

We take reasonable precautions to protect your information from loss, misuse or alteration. Our vendors, contractors or partners who have access to your information in connection with providing services for us are required to keep the information confidential and are not permitted to use this information for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for us.

Your information will generally be stored in our databases, which are located in the United States. For easier processing of e-mail communications, or other marketing purposes, however, your information may be sent to countries outside the United States.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a small file stored on a user’s hard drive containing information about that user. We use cookies on this website to improve your user experience. Our cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. A user that does not accept cookies may not be able to use all portions or functionality of this website.

**Web Beacons**  
Web beacons are small pieces of code placed on a Web page to monitor the behavior and collect data about the visitors viewing a Web page. For example, Web beacons can be used to count the users who visit a Web page or to deliver a cookie to the browser of a visitor viewing that page. We may use Web beacons on this website from time to time for this and other purposes.

**Do Not Track**  
At this time, we do not respond to “Do Not Track” signals sent from Web browsers.

**Online Tracking**  
Third parties may collect personally identifiable information about an individual user's online activities over time and across different websites when a user uses this website.

Below are links to resources regarding different types of online tracking:

For the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>

For more information on Pardot: <http://www.pardot.com/company/legal/privacy-policy/>

**Safe Harbor Privacy Policy**  
AccessData complies with the U.S.-E.U. Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. We have certified that we adhere to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view our certification, visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.

This Safe Harbor Privacy Policy describes how we handle personal information (1) collected by us, our customers, and other business partners located in the European Economic Area (the “EEA”), which may then be transferred to us in the United States; and (2) received from companies that use our services who operate in the EEA and processed by us in the United States on behalf of the company. This Safe Harbor Privacy Policy supplements the AccessData Privacy Statement found at: <http://accessdata.com/privacy-statement>.

**Notice and Choice**  
To the extent permitted by the Safe Harbor Frameworks, we reserve the right to process personal information in the course of providing professional services to our clients without the knowledge of individuals involved. Where we collect personal information directly from individuals in the EU, and/or Switzerland, we inform them about the types of personal information we collect from them, the purposes for which we collect and use it, and the types of non-agent third parties to which we disclose that information. We also inform those individuals about the choices and means, if any, we offer individuals for limiting the use or disclosure of their information.

We will offer individuals the opportunity to choose (opt-out) whether their personal information is (a) to be disclosed to a non-agent third party, or (b) to be used for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual.

For sensitive personal information, we will give individuals the opportunity to affirmatively and explicitly (opt-in) consent to the disclosure of the information to a non-agent third party or the use of the information for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual.

**Disclosures and Transfers**  
In cases of onward transfers of information to third parties, we will obtain assurances from third party business partners (agents) that they will safeguard personal information consistent with our policies (for example, a contract obligating the third party to use at least the same level of protection as is required by the relevant Safe Harbor Principles).

We will not disclose an individual’s personal information to third parties, except where one or more of the following conditions is true:

  * We have the individual’s permission to make the disclosure;
  * The disclosure is required by law or professional standards;
  * The disclosure is reasonably related to the sale or disposition of all or part of our business;
  * The information in question is publicly available;
  * The disclosure is reasonably necessary for the establishment or defense of legal claims;
  * or
  * The disclosure is to another AccessData entity or to persons or entities providing services on our or the individual’s behalf (each a “transferee”), consistent with the purpose for which the information was obtained, if the transferee, with respect to the information in question: 
    * is subject to law providing an adequate level of privacy protection;
    * has agreed in writing to provide an adequate level of privacy protection; or
    * subscribes to the Principles.

Permitted transfers of information, either to third parties or within AccessData, include the transfer of data from one jurisdiction to another, including transfers to and from the United States of America. Because privacy laws vary from one jurisdiction to another, personal information may be transferred to a jurisdiction where the laws provide less or different protection than the jurisdiction in which the information originated.

**Information Collected by AccessData, Corporate Customers and Business Partners**  
We may receive personal information from our corporate customers and other business partners in the EEA, such as name, email address, company name, title, postal address, telephone number, and preferences regarding our applications, websites, and services. Any personal information sent to us may be used by us and our agents and business partners for the purposes described at the time the information was collected. If you agree to receive email or telephone marketing from us, personal information we receive will also be used for those purposes, as described in the AccessData Privacy Statement. If we plan to use personal information for a purpose that is incompatible with these purposes or if we plan to disclose personal information to a kind of company not described here, we will seek your consent to such uses or disclosures.

**Agents and Service Providers**  
We may work with other companies to help us deliver our services to you on our behalf. In some cases, these companies will have access to some of your personal information in order to provide services to you on our behalf. They are not permitted to use your information for their own purposes. We require that our agents and service providers that have access to personal information received by us from the EU or Switzerland subscribe to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles, be subject to the EU Privacy Directive or another adequacy finding, or enter into a written agreement that requires them to provide at least the same level of privacy protection as is required by the relevant Safe Harbor Principles.

**Security**  
We use reasonable physical, electronic, and administrative safeguards to protect your personal information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

**Data Integrity**  
We take reasonable steps to ensure that personal information we process is accurate, complete, and current by using the most recent information provided to us.

**Information Processed by AccessData on behalf of a Company Using an AccessData Service**  
We provide services to companies (learn more at http://accessdata.com/products-services/professional-services). As part of providing these services, we may receive and process your personal information if you are a customer of one of these companies. We act on the instructions of these companies and uses reasonable physical, electronic, and administrative safeguards to protect this personal information from loss, misuse, or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction.

Companies that use an AccessData service are responsible for complying with all other obligations in relation to the personal information they may collect from you. We require that the company using our services, in which personal information is received by us from the EU or Switzerland, subscribe to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles, be subject to the EU Privacy Directive or another adequacy finding, or enter into a written agreement that requires them to provide at least the same level of privacy protection as is required by the relevant Safe Harbor Principles.

Individuals whose information we hold may request, and we will provide, access to the information and the opportunity to correct, amend or delete that information where it is inaccurate, except where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks posed to the individual’s privacy in the case in question, or where the rights of persons other than the individual would be violated.

**Access**  
See Changing Your Account Information above in the AccessData Privacy Statement.

**Enforcement**  
We have put in place mechanisms to verify our ongoing adherence to these privacy principles. Please contact us at [legal@accessdata.com](mailto:legal@accessdata.com) with any questions or concerns regarding the use or disclosure of personal information.

We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding the use and disclosure of personal information by reference to the principles contained in this Safe Harbor Privacy Policy. We have selected the European Data Protection Authorities Panel and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commission as our external dispute resolution mechanism in the event that a complaint cannot be resolved internally.

We utilize the self-assessment approach to assure our compliance with this Safe Harbor Privacy Policy. We periodically verify that this Safe Harbor Privacy Policy is accurate, comprehensive for the information intended to be covered, prominently displayed, completely implemented, and in conformity with the Principles. We encourage interested persons to raise any concerns with us using the contact information below. We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of personal information in accordance with the principles contained in this Safe Harbor Privacy Policy.

**Changes or Updates**  
This Safe Harbor Privacy Policy may change from time to time as permitted under the Safe Harbor program.

**Limitation on Application of Principles**  
Adherence by AccessData to these Safe Harbor Principles may be limited (a) to the extent required to respond to a legal or ethical obligation; (b) to the extent necessary to meet national security, public interest or law enforcement obligations; and (c) to the extent expressly permitted by an applicable law, rule or regulation.

**You Can Opt-out of Receiving Further Marketing from AccessData**  
Periodically, we may send you information about our various products and services, or the products and services we feel may be of interest to you. Please contact us at [legal@accessdata.com](mailto:legal@accessdata.com) if you do not want to receive such information.

**Posting to Public Areas**  
Please remember that if you post any of your personal information in public areas of this website such as in online forums, webinars, or chat rooms, such information may be collected and used by others over whom we have no control. We are not responsible for the use made by third parties of information you post or otherwise make available in public areas of this website.

**Notice Regarding Children**  
We do not knowingly collect personal information from individuals under age 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal information through this website. If you have reason to believe that we may have accidentally received personal information from an individual under age 13, please contact us immediately at legal@accessdata.com.

**Intellectual Property Rights**  
The elements of this website, including graphics, logos, images, designs, sounds information and documents (the “Materials”), are protected by copyright, trademark, trade dress trade secret, unfair competition and other laws and are owned by AccessData Group, LLC and our subsidiaries, divisions and affiliates, or by our suppliers, vendors or other third parties who have contributed Materials to this website (each a “Supplier”). In no event shall any of the Materials be copied, reproduced, distributed, displayed, downloaded, stored in a retrieval system or transmitted in any form without the prior express written permission of AccessData and/or our Supplier. The AccessData products and brands mentioned in this website are registered trademarks or trademarks of AccessData in the United States and/or other countries. The names of actual products and companies mentioned in this website may be registered trademarks or trademarks of their respective owners. Any rights not expressly granted herein are reserved.

**General Disclaimer**  
THE MATERIALS ON THIS WEBSITE COULD INCLUDE INACCURACIES OR TYPOGRAPHICAL ERRORS AND ARE SUBJECT TO CHANGE AT ANY TIME. THE MATERIALS ARE PROVIDED “AS IS” WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND. TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW, ACCESSDATA AND OUR SUPPLIERS HEREBY DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES, EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, AND CONDITIONS WITH RESPECT TO THE MATERIALS, THEIR QUALITY, PERFORMANCE, SUITABILITY, MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, TITLE AND NON-INFRINGEMENT.

**Links to Other Websites**  
As a convenience to you, this website may contain links to websites controlled by parties other than AccessData. We are not responsible for and do not endorse the privacy practices or content of third party websites. We recommend that you carefully read the privacy policies of each site you visit.

**Limitation of Liability**  
IN NO EVENT WILL ACCESSDATA AND OUR SUPPLIERS BE LIABLE FOR INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT OR TORT, ARISING OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE MATERIALS AVAILABLE ON THIS WEBSITE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. IN PARTICULAR, AND WITHOUT LIMITATION, ACCESSDATA SHALL HAVE NO LIABILITY FOR ANY LOSS OF USE, DATA, INCLUDING THE COSTS OF RECOVERING SUCH DATA, OR PROFITS.

**Privacy-Related Inquiries and Complaints**  
We take privacy concerns seriously. Please contact us at[ **legal@accessdata.com**](mailto:legal@accessdata.com) if you believe that we have not complied with this Privacy Statement with respect to your personal information or you have other related inquiries or concerns. Please describe in as much detail as possible, the nature of your inquiry or the ways in which you believe that this Privacy Statement has not been complied with. We will investigate your inquiry or complaint promptly.

**Contact Us**  
We are committed to responding to your questions and comments. Please send us your questions or comments regarding this Privacy Statement or your information to [legal@accessdata.com](mailto:legal@accessdata.com). 588 West 400 South Lindon Utah 84042 | 801.377.5410 | [support@accessdata.com](mailto:support@accessdata.com) © 2017 AccessData Group, LLC All Rights Reserved | Privacy Statement (http://accessdata.com/about/privacy-statement) We self-certify compliance with: (<https://safeharbor.export.gov/list.aspx>) (<http://export.gov/safeharbor//index.asp>)
